[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 27]
[제27화]
It ends like this again.
또 이런 결말이네
Is this
이대로
truly the end?
끝인 건가?
Zhaomin.
사저
The detox pill I just gave you
방금 복용하신 것은 석독단입니다
is for countering demonic energy.
마기를 없애는 특효약이니
It should be working by now.
이제 곧 약효가 나타날 겁니다
Any more left?
더 없느냐?
No.
없습니다
I only got two from Elder Dongyang.
동양 사백님께 겨우 두 알을 얻어 왔는데
Too bad he's not here.
하필 지금은 안 계시니…
What do we do now?
그럼 어쩐단 말이냐?
Let's find Master and the others.
우선 사부님 일행부터 찾죠
You go ahead.
먼저 가거라
I'm going to save Lifei.
난 소사매를 구하러 가겠다
You...
혼자서 말입니까?
Fine.
알겠습니다
Zhaomin, be careful.
사저, 부디 몸조심해야 합니다
Don't draw any attention.
절대 무리하지 마십시오
Wait until our backup arrives.
저희 지원군이 올 때까지 기다리십시오
Got it.
알았다
Zhaomin.
사저
What is it?
왜 그러느냐?
We'll talk later.
할 말은 나중에 하자꾸나
Just go save them.
어서 사람들을 구해
Will you submit or not
굴복하겠느냐?
Huolian Abbey
우리 화련관은
will never side with demons!
절대 마족과 손을 잡지 않는다
You.
너
Come here!
이리 오너라
Qiongqi, come at me!
궁기, 내게 덤벼라
Master!
사부님
Hang in there!
조금만 버티세요
Watch out!
조심하거라
You're finally here!
드디어 왔구나
Where did you hide the Lei Xiuyuan
날 해치지 않겠다던 뇌수원은
who promised never to hurt me?
어디로 간 거야?
Lifei.
려비
I will never hurt you.
난 영원히 널 해치지 않아
Lei Xiuyuan, let Lifei go!
뇌수원, 소사매를 놓아줘
Zhaomin.
사저
You're not him.
너는 그 사람이 아니야
You are Yecha!
넌 야차야
Lifei, forgive me.
려비, 날 용서해다오
Only by breaking through your seals
네가 봉인을 뚫어야
can I truly protect you.
진정으로 너를 지킬 수 있어
You've fully shed your shell.
이제 완전히 탈바꿈했구나
No one can ever hurt you again.
더는 그 누구도 너를 해치지 못할 거다
Not even me.
나를 포함해서 말이지
This time,
이번만큼은...
I kept my word.
약속을 어기지 않았어
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
Xiuyuan.
수원
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스하게 품어줄까♪
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪마음을 전할 길조차 없는데♪
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪Last night's stars cast faint glimmers♪
♪어젯밤 하늘을 수놓던 아스라한 별빛♪
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그때는 어찌 당연하게 여겼을까♪
♪With a heartbroken cry♪
♪가슴이 찢어지는 듯한 애달픈 외침으로♪
♪I wish you well♪
♪오직 그대의 안녕만을 바라네♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
No.
안 돼
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목 놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
No!
안 돼
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
No!
안 돼
♪Leaping straight into that heartbreaking past♪
♪내 기꺼이 이 몸을 던지리라, 살을 도려내는 듯한 아픈 기억 속으로♪
♪Just to keep you safe♪
♪그대만 무사할 수 있다면♪
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨결이 점차 희미해지고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪맞잡은 그 손을 더는 쥘 수 없으니♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 다가올 시린 바람과 안개를♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪이제 누구와 함께 견뎌내야 할까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪미소를 지으며 눈을 감는 것은♪
No! No!
안 돼, 안 돼
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪나로 인해 그대 슬피 울까 염려되어♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪말없이 공명등 한 줄기 빛이 되어♪
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪그대가 걷는 어두운 밤길을 비추어주리♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
No!
안 돼
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목 놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
Xiuyuan!
수원
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪I'd shatter my soul♪
♪살을 도려내는 듯한 아픔으로♪
♪To lay all your days in peace♪
♪남은 그대의 인생이 부디 평탄하기를♪
♪Who says that love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped?♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 누가 알랴♪
♪I will level the seas and mountains♪
♪내 저 산과 바다를 평정하고♪
♪Break the waves, no matter how mad it seems♪
♪풍랑이 미쳐 날뛴대도 두렵지가 않네♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
♪Torn inside, still I burn bright♪
♪가슴이 무너져 내릴지라도 참으로 감미롭구나♪
♪With the light from my fingertips, I build a paradise♪
♪내 손끝에 맺힌 마지막 빛으로 그대와 함께할 낙원을 세워♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪영원히 그대 곁을 거닐고 싶어라♪
Ye.
엽 오라버니
How is it?
어찌 되었습니까?
- Are you okay? - Lu?
- 괜찮으십니까 - 육 사형
Lu?
육 사형
Gelin?
가림
You talked about forever.
평생을 함께하자더니
What would I do if you died?
사형이 죽으면 저는 어떡합니까
Gelin.
가림아
I...
나...
Don't say anything.
뭐요? 어쨌든
Just stay alive.
살아남아야 합니다
Look. What is it?
사형, 이게 뭡니까?
The demonic energy has all been purified by it.
마기가 정화되고 있습니다
Lifei.
려비
Where are you hurt?
대체 어디를 다친 게냐?
I killed Xiuyuan.
제가 수원을 죽였습니다
That's Xiuyuan's blood?
그게 수원의 피인 거야?
Did you...?
설마...
What happened?
어찌 된 일이야?
He's dead.
수원이 죽었습니다
- Lifei! - Zhaomin.
- 려비, 려비 - 사저
Calm down.
진정하거라
This isn't your fault.
네 잘못이 아니다
It's all my fault.
전부 저 때문입니다
I should be the one dead.
죽어야 하는 사람은 저인데...
No.
아니다
He deserved to die.
죽어야 할 자는 그자였다
He was a demon.
그자는 마족이다
Our enemy.
우리의 적이란 말이다
Zhaomin.
사저
Who did this?
누구 짓이냐?
Who killed Zhaomin?
대체 누가 사저를 죽인 것이냐?
It was me.
접니다
It's all my fault.
전부 저 때문입니다
The Divine Tree colluded with the Demon Lord
건목이 마군과 결탁하여
to overthrow the immortal sects.
선문을 무너뜨리려 했다
Seize her!
붙잡아라
Your Highness,
기 왕야
what do you mean by this?
이게 무슨 짓이오
She's a demon!
저 아이는 마족입니다
If she hadn't used the Divine Tree's power
만약 이 아이가 건목의 힘으로
to purify the demonic energy,
이곳의 마기를 정화하지 않았다면
you would all have been
당신들은
killed by the demons.
진즉에 마족의 손에 목숨을 잃었을 것이오
But she is the Divine Tree.
그렇다 한들 건목 때문이 아니오
The demon attack
마족이 기습해 온 것 또한
happened because of her.
저 아이 때문에 비롯된 일이니
She's a walking disaster.
저 아이야말로 모든 화의 화근이오
Who's the disaster?
누가 화근이라는 겁니까
Wasn't today's fiasco enough?
낮에 벌인 그 난동으로도 부족하단 말입니까
If you hadn't coveted the Divine Tree
당신들이 건목을 탐내어
and insisted on that public trial,
굳이 공심을 열겠다고 고집하지만 않았어도
Wuyue Court wouldn't have been caught off guard!
우리 무월정이 이토록 큰 피해를 보았겠습니까?
And Elder Guangwei,
제 사숙님과
Zhaomin,
사저
and so many others wouldn't have...
그리고 무월정의 수많은 제자가 어찌 이리...
This demon attack
이번 마족의 습격으로 인해
has severely wounded the immortal sects.
우리 선문은 원기를 크게 상했소
We don't know what the Demon Lord has planned next.
마군이 또 어떤 수작을 부릴지 알 수 없는 노릇이니
I suggest
내 생각에는
you all return
여러 선배님들께서 일단 각자의 처소로 돌아가
and tend to your wounds.
부상을 치료하며 휴식을 취하심이 옳을 듯하오
Don't give the demons another opening.
마족에게 다시는 빈틈을 보여선 안 되니까 말이오
We'll discuss
나머지 일들은
everything else later.
추후에 다시 논하도록 하시오
Xingzheng Hall was wiped out long ago!
성정관은 이미 멸문당하지 않았소?
Why should we listen to you?
우리가 어찌 당신 말을 따라야 하겠소?
Everyone, stay still! Behave!
모두 움직이지 마라, 얌전히 있거라
Xingzheng Hall
우리 성정관은
fell victim to Zong Quan, who colluded with demons.
마족과 결탁했던 종권에게 참변을 당해
Though we suffered losses,
비록 큰 희생을 치렀으나
we still stand unbroken.
여전히 당당히 살아남아 이 땅에 서 있소
Can't you all learn from that?
여러 사문께서는 어찌 이를 교훈으로 삼지 않으시는 게요?
Fine.
그만두겠소
Defending against the demons matters.
마족을 막아내는 것이 우선이니 말이오
Thank you for the reminder, Your Highness.
일깨워 주셔서 감사하오, 왕야
We're leaving.
우리는 이만 물러가겠소
- Go! - Go.
- 가자 - 가자
[In Memory of Zhaomin]
[소민의 묘]
Lifei, wake up.
려비, 일어나거라
Lifei, wake up!
소사매, 어서 일어나렴
Carry yourself like a girl.
여인이라면 모름지기 여인다워야지
Be graceful and proper.
품행도 단정히 하고
No more clumsiness.
다시는 덜렁대거나 덤벙거려선 안 된다
Understand?
알겠느냐?
Lifei.
소사매
Take care.
부디 몸조심하거라
Zhaomin,
사저
I'll listen to you from now on.
이제부터는 사저 말을 잘 들을게요
Please don't be mad at me.
그러니 제발 저한테 화내지 마세요
Zhaomin loved you so much.
사저께서 너를 그토록 아끼셨는데
She wouldn't be mad at you.
어찌 네게 화를 내시겠느냐
[In Memory of Zhaomin]
[소민의 묘]
Zhaomin.
사저
I bought
이것들은요
these for you in Duanming City.
제가 단명성에서 사저 주려고 산 선물입니다
Peepshow scrolls,
움직이는 화첩도 있고
assorted preserved fruits,
과일 정과도 있으며
and lotus incense.
그리고 부용향도 있습니다
I always wanted to give them to you.
사실 진작에 드리고 싶었는데
But I never had the courage.
그동안 도저히 용기가 나지 않아 못 드렸습니다
I'll go check on Master.
전 사부님께 가보겠습니다
[In Memory of Guangwei]
[광미의 묘]
Here, Guangwei.
이보게, 광 씨
Drink.
한잔하시죠
Master,
사부님
you're hurt. You shouldn't drink.
몸도 다치셨으면서 술을 드시면 어떡합니까
Besides,
게다가
Elder Guangwei was aloof
사백께서는 속세의 때가 묻지 않고
and serious.
늘 엄격하고 올곧으셨으니
He probably didn't like wine.
아마 술은 좋아하지 않으셨을 겁니다
Bring him tea next time.
다음부터는 차를 올리세요
Since when did you start fussing over people?
너는 어째서 벌써 잔소리를 늘어놓는 게냐?
You're becoming more and more like Zhaomin.
갈수록 소민을 닮아가는구나
Did you go see Zhaomin?
사저 무덤에는 다녀왔느냐?
If it weren't for saving me,
저를 구하려던 게 아니었다면
Zhaomin wouldn't have died.
사저께서 돌아가실 일도 없었을 겁니다
It's all my fault.
다 저 때문입니다
First, Master.
처음에는 사부님
Then Elder Guangwei.
그다음에는 광미 사백님과
Zhaomin.
사저
And Xiuyuan.
그리고 수원까지
I used to call him a jinx.
예전에는 화근이라 하였는데
Turns out I'm the real jinx.
알고 보니 화를 불러들인 건 저였습니다
Alright.
그만하거라
Stop overthinking.
쓸데없는 생각은 그만두거라
You and Xiuyuan
너와 수원은
were both caught up in fate.
둘 다 숙명에 얽매이고 휩쓸린 이들이다
Some things
세상에는
are hard to explain.
말로 다 설명할 수 없는 일도 있는 법이지
But one thing is clear.
하지만 한 가지 확실한 것은 있다
They all wanted you to live well.
그들 모두가 네가 살아남기를 바랐다는 점이다
Don't let them down.
그러니 그들의 뜻을 저버리지 말거라
Elder Guangwei?
사백님이?
Was it him who woke Xiuyuan?
사백님이 수원을 깨우신 건가요?
Guangwei
네 광미 사백이
used the last of his strength.
마지막 남은 힘을 모두 짜내신 게지
He channeled the Heart-Cleansing Art
그가 수원의 이마에 불어넣은 것은
into Xiuyuan's forehead.
척심결이었다
The Heart-Cleansing Art?
척심결이요?
It can
척심결은
dissolve the demon's Soul-Bewitching Vines.
마족의 사술인 미혼만을 정화할 수 있지
In the last Sea Calamity,
지난번 해운의 대전 때
we saw too many of the monsters
우리는 미혼만에 당한 요족들을
infected by those vines.
수없이 보아왔다
They lost themselves,
그들 역시 수원과 마찬가지로
just like Xiuyuan,
본성을 잃어버린 채
and became violent and bloodthirsty.
살육만을 탐하며 포악해졌었지
But you know
한데 너도 알지 않느냐
that wasn't Xiuyuan's true self.
그것이 결코 수원의 본심이 아니었음을
I know.
압니다
But I still killed him.
하지만 결국 제가 수원이를 죽였습니다
In that moment,
그 순간
I gave it everything I had to kill him.
저는 온 힘을 다해 내리쳤단 말입니다
He'd rather die by my hand
수원은 저에게 상처를 입힐까 두려워
than hurt me.
차라리 제 손에 죽는 길을 택한 겁니다
If you're hurting, just cry.
괴로우면 참지 말고 울거라
You'll feel better.
실컷 울고 나면 마음이 한결 편해질 게다
Master.
사부님
I'm so scared.
저는 너무 무섭습니다
I'm afraid of dragging more of you down.
제가 또다시 여러분께 화를 끼칠까 봐
Afraid of watching more people die before me.
제 눈앞에서 또 누군가 죽어갈까 봐 두려워요
I can't take it anymore.
이제는 정말 버틸 힘이 없습니다
I liked you better
내가 보기에는
the way you used to be.
네가 예전만 못하구나
You were so carefree.
예전의 그 쾌활하고 대범하던 모습이 없구나
If you ask me,
내 한마디하마
life and death are just fate.
삶과 죽음은 하늘에 달렸고
Let things take their course.
인연 또한 하늘이 정하는 법이다
Don't carry everything on your own shoulders.
모든 짐을 네 어깨에 짊어지려 하지 말거라
The Sea Calamity looms, and human hearts run deep.
해운이 임박하여 세상인심이 이토록 흉흉하니
You've already severed your worldly ties.
네가 이미 세상의 미련과 인연을 끊어냈다면
Why not just leave?
차라리 이대로 떠나 숨어 지내는 게 어떻겠느냐?
Find a place to live in seclusion,
네 청성 사부가 그랬던 것처럼
just like Qingcheng.
조용한 곳을 찾아 은거하란 말이다
I believe
이 넓고 넓은 천지에
there must be a place for you
정녕 네 몸 하나
in this vast world.
누일 곳이 없겠느냐
I'm the Divine Tree after all.
저는 결국 건목이니까요
There's no place for me in this life.
이번 생에 제가 머물 곳은 더는 없습니다
Your Highness.
기 왕야
Mr. Luo.
나 선배
You're still here?
아직 떠나지 않으셨소?
I'm worried about the safety of the immortal sects.
나는 선문의 안위가 걱정되어
I can neither eat nor sleep.
도저히 잠을 이룰 수가 없더군
After much thought,
고심한 끝에
I'd like to share
마음속에 둔 몇 마디 말을
some honest words with you.
왕야와 함께 의논해 보고자 왔소
Mr. Luo, go on.
나 선배, 말씀하시오
After the battle at Wuyue Court,
무월정에서의 전투로
the immortal sects are badly weakened
선문은 원기를 크게 상했고
and divided.
인심마저 흩어졌소
They're in no shape to fight the demons again.
이래서야 마족과 다시 맞서기란 불가능하지
But your influence is at its peak.
반면에 기 왕야께서는 지금 위세가 하늘을 찌르니
And the Divine Tree trusts you completely.
건목 또한 왕야를 깊이 신뢰하고 있지 않소?
I believe
내가 생각하기에
you could use the Divine Tree to command the world.
왕야께서 건목을 거느리고 천하를 호령하시면 어떻겠소?
Lifei is the disciple of Elder Qingcheng and Elder Chongyi,
려비는 청성과 충이 선배님의 제자이자
and my closest friend.
내게 가장 소중한 지기요
Anyone who schemes against her or tries to harm her
누구든 다시 그 아이를 탐내거나 다치게 하려 든다면
is my enemy.
그것은 나 기동주와 적이 되겠다는 뜻이오
No matter who they are,
상대가 누구든 상관없이
I will slaughter their entire clan
내 반드시 그들을 멸문시키고
to the very last.
죽는 날까지 끝까지 쫓을 것이오
Guess I spoke out of turn.
내가 경솔했구려
Alright then.
그렇다면
I'm leaving.
이만 가보겠소
See yourself out.
배웅은 않겠소
Ungrateful fool.
은혜도 모르는 것 같으니라고
I offer you good counsel,
좋은 뜻으로 도와주려 했건만
and you reject it.
고마운 줄도 모르다니
If I weren't wounded,
내게 부상만 없었어도
you'd never get to claim the Divine Tree
네가 건목을 독차지하고
and lord it over me.
내 앞에서 거드름을 피우게 두진 않았을 터다
Who's there?
누구냐
You?
너구나
Patrols must be tightened this time.
이번 순찰은 경계를 대폭 강화해야 한다
If the Divine Tree appears,
만약 건목이 나타나면
capture it alive.
반드시 생포하도록 해라
Go patrol.
가서 순찰해라
Guardian,
호법님
has the Lord awakened?
존상께서는 깨어나셨습니까?
Why isn't he awake yet?
어째서 아직도 깨어나지 못하는 겁니까?
Everyone is waiting.
모두가 기다리고 있습니다
If he never wakes up...
만약 깨어나지 못하신다면...
Qiongqi!
궁기!
Guardian,
호법님
we've lain low for centuries.
우리가 수백 년을 잠복하며
We've come so far.
겨우 여기까지 왔습니다
We have to have a backup plan.
대책을 세워두지 않을 수 없지 않습니까
Think of all our people.
이 많은 족인이
Are we supposed to
설마 이곳에서
just wait here forever?
기약도 없이 기다려야 한단 말입니까?
If the Lord hadn't been too soft
존상께서 마음이 약해지셔서
to absorb the Divine Tree,
건목을 흡수하려 하지 않으셨다면
it wouldn't have come to this.
이렇게 되진 않을 겁니다
Silence!
닥쳐라
The Lord will not die.
존상께서는 절대 죽지 않으신다
Yes.
예
The Lord is the supreme ruler of our clan.
존상은 우리 종족의 지존이시니
He'll never be defeated by those petty immortals!
선문의 하찮은 자들에게 절대 패하지 않으실 겁니다
He's a little demon.
이 아이는 어린 마두야
I need to kill him!
지금 내가 해야 할 일은 이 아이를 단칼에 베는 것이다
Even if he's the Demon Lord,
설령 마군이라 한들
he's still a life.
이 또한 하나의 생명이네
Besides,
게다가
he's returned to his original state now.
지금은 본래의 마음을 되찾았으니
There's no good or evil in him.
여기에 무슨 선과 악의 구분이 있겠나
Here.
자
You won't eat radish porridge.
무죽도 안 먹고
And you spit out the sweet potato.
고구마는 도로 뱉어내다니
This is milk I stole
이건 내가 암호랑이에게서
from that tiger.
몰래 얻어 온 젖이란다
Just try a little.
조금이라도 맛보렴
What do you even want?
도대체 무엇을 원하는 걸까?
You two...
너희 둘은
You two were meant to be together.
너희 둘은 함께할 운명이로구나
Master,
사부님
why hasn't he grown
이 아이는 어째서 수백 년이나 키웠는데도
in all these centuries?
도무지 자라지 않는 겁니까?
[Young Hu Jiaping] Is he some kind of monster?
[소년 호가평] 괴물이 아닙니까?
Don't talk nonsense.
쓸데없는 소리 마라
Go.
가서
Deliver this letter to Chufeng Academy.
추봉서원에 서찰이나 좀 전하고 오너라
Resentment is a net,
원망은 그물과 같아서
trapping both user and prey.
남을 가두고 자신을 옭아맨다
Only by breaking free
그 그물을 풀고 가야만
can the soul find peace.
비로소 자유를 얻으리라
Graceful as bamboo,
풍채는 곧은 대나무 같고
virtue known afar.
덕망은 천하에 드높으리니
From now on,
오늘부터
your name will be Lei Xiuyuan.
네 이름은 뇌수원이다
Here.
자
Pay your respects to the Crown Prince.
태자 전하를 뵙거라
Greetings, Your Royal Highness.
태자 전하를 뵙습니다
No need for formalities.
예를 차릴 것 없다
My name is Ye Ye.
내 이름은 엽엽이다
Let's study and play together
앞으로 나와 함께 글도 배우고
from now on.
함께 놀자꾸나
No way?
설마요
Me? Acting Sect Leader?
저더러 대리 장문을 맡으라는 말씀입니까?
We old ones are either wounded
우리는 모두 큰 부상을 입어
or broken.
몸이 성치 않게 되었다
You younger ones are either too badly hurt
젊은 제자들은 중상을 입었거나
or still too inexperienced.
아직 수행이 부족하지 않으냐
So,
그러니
you are
네가 대리 장문을 맡는 것이
the best choice.
가장 적절하구나
I'm the worst choice.
제가 맡는 것이야말로 가장 부적절합니다
Sir,
사숙님
you know me.
제 성품을 잘 아시지 않습니까
I... I'm
저, 저는 말입니다
naturally lazy.
워낙 덜렁대는 성격이라
I really can't do it.
도저히 감당할 수 없습니다
You think
네가 아무리 산만한들
you're lazier than me?
나보다 더 하겠느냐?
You want to talk about being lazy?
나와 산만함을 겨루어 보겠다는 게냐?
You have a strong sense of right and wrong.
너는 옳고 그름을 분명히 가릴 줄 알고
You're chivalrous and courageous.
협기가 넘치며
You don't follow the crowd.
결코 세파에 휩쓸리지 않지
That's more than enough.
그것만으로도 충분하다
We trust you
네가 대리 장문을 맡아 준다면
to be the acting Sect Leader.
우리 모두 널 믿으마
This is wrong.
안 됩니다, 안 돼요
Xiguang.
계광아
Master.
사부님
It's our fault.
모두 우리 늙은이들이 무능한 탓이다
At the critical moment,
존망의 위기에 처했는데도
we're all too wounded and weak
이리 늙고 병들어
to take care of ourselves.
제 몸 하나 추스르지 못하니 말이다
We have no choice but to place this heavy burden
결국 이 무거운 중책을
on you.
네게 의탁할 수밖에 없구나
Master!
사부님
Please. I can't accept this.
제게 이리하시면 제가 감당치 못합니다
I'm not capable enough.
사숙도 힘이 미치지 못해
I'm ashamed.
참으로 부끄럽구나
Ma'am.
사숙님
Master.
사부님
Don't say that.
그리 말씀하지 마십시오
I've been a terrible disciple.
제가 불효한 탓입니다
It's easy
효도하는 제자가 되는 길은
to change that.
간단하다
Just agree to be
우리의 부탁을 들어다오
the acting Sect Leader.
대리 장문을 맡아다오
Alright.
되었다
I'll notify everyone as soon as possible.
각 문파에 네가 대리 장문이 되었음을 알리마
Do a good job.
부디 잘 이끌어다오
Zhaomin,
사저
I never thought the nightmare I had on Fanghu Island would come true.
방호도에서 꾸었던 악몽이 기어이 현실이 되었습니다
They actually want me to be acting Sect Leader.
장로들께서 제게 대리 장문을 맡기셨습니다
I...
저는...
It's not that I'm scared.
실은 겁이 나는 게 아닙니다
Fine. I'm just scared.
역시 겁이 납니다
I'm afraid I won't do a good job.
이 장문 직을 제대로 수행하지 못할까 두렵습니다
You know me.
사저도 저를 잘 아시지 않습니까
I'm a free spirit.
저는 그저 게으르고 되는대로 살아온 사람인데
I can't handle this kind of responsibility.
이런 무거운 짐을 어찌 짊어진단 말입니까
I have no choice now.
아무래도 지금은 방도가 없으니
I'm planning to sneak down the mountain tonight.
야반도주라도 해서 산에서 내려갈까 합니다
I'll run far away.
멀리 숨어 버릴 테니
Let them find another disciple for this position.
다른 사형이나 사제를 찾아보시라 하지요
I thought you'd be reliable in a crisis.
중대한 순간에는 네가 믿음직한 아이라 여겼거늘
Never expected you to disappoint me so much!
이토록 나를 실망하게 하는구나
If you run,
네가 도망쳐 버린다면
who will protect Lifei, Simo,
누가 나를 대신해 려비와 사묵
and the other juniors?
그리고 다른 사제와 사매들을 지켜 주겠느냐?
Who will look after the injured elders?
늙고 병약하신 사부님들은 또 누가 보살핀단 말이냐
Xiguang,
계광
you've run away once before.
이미 한 차례 도망친 적이 있지 않느냐
Don't run
이번만큼은
and hide again this time.
다시 도망치거나 물러서지 말거라
Zhao...
사...
Zhaomin!
사저
Don't worry!
염려 마십시오
I'll take good care of them
제가 반드시 사저를 대신해
for you.
그들을 잘 보살피겠습니다
Deng may seem unreliable,
등 사형은 겉보기엔 덤벙대는 것 같지만
but he's thoughtful,
실은 매우 치밀하고
honorable,
정정당당하시니
and far better than most.
타인보다 훨씬 나을 겁니다
Wuyue Court will thrive
무월정을 그분께 맡긴다면
under his leadership.
분명 지금보다 더 잘 이끌 겁니다
You seem to be in better spirits
요 며칠 사이에
these past few days.
기운을 좀 차린 듯하구나
Staying a broken mess
반송장 같은 몰골로 있어 봐야
would only worry Master
사부님 마음만 무겁게 해 드리고
and everyone else.
모두에게 짐이 될 뿐입니다
I don't want to be a burden.
저는 짐이 되고 싶지 않습니다
Being with you is a blessing,
너와 함께할 수 있는 것은
if anything.
크나큰 복이라고 해야지
Lifei.
려비
I know
네가 줄곧 수원 때문에
you've been grieving over Xiuyuan.
마음 아파한다는 걸 알아
But
하지만 실은
Rakshasa took him away.
나찰에게 구해졌으니
Maybe he's still alive.
어쩌면 무사할지도 모르는 일이다
The Fragrance Bond is gone.
천향인이 이미 사라졌습니다
He's really not here anymore.
수원은 정말 세상을 떠났습니다
Lifei.
려비
Let the past
지나간 일은
stay in the past.
잊거라
Think about the people
지금 네 곁에 있는
still by your side.
이들을 더 생각해야지
Oh,
참
how's Ye Ye?
엽엽은 어찌 되었습니까?
He was badly hurt saving me that day.
그날 저를 구하려다 크게 다치셨는데
I haven't seen him in days.
요 며칠간 보이지 않구나
Wasn't he taken away
엽엽은
by Sect Leader Miao?
묘 문주가 데려간 것 아니더냐?
Changyue and Ye Ye wouldn't just leave without a word.
창월과 엽엽은 아무 말도 없이 떠났을 리 없습니다
Could something have happened?
무슨 일이 생긴 건 아닐까요?
Don't panic.
너무 걱정하지 말거라
Maybe he was wounded and unconscious,
어쩌면 부상이 심해 혼절한 채
and the Dizang Sect disciples took him back.
지장문의 사형제들이 데려갔을지도 모르니
I'll send someone to ask.
사람을 보내 알아보마
Alright.
예
Lifei,
소사매
Master said you need to
사부님께서 챙겨 주라고
drink this medicine.
당부하신 약이란다
Thanks.
고맙습니다, 사형
I haven't seen Master all afternoon.
그런데 오전 내내 사부님이 안 보이시네요
Where did he go?
어디 가셨습니까?
He went to Hushe Peak.
사부님은 호사봉에 가셨단다
The horn of the Si beast. [*Divine one-horned animal]
사지각이라...
Master!
사부님
What are you doing here?
어찌 이곳에 오셨습니까?
I want to
이곳을
fix this place up.
다시 손을 봐야겠다
Look how messy it is.
무척이나 어지럽구나
Let me do it.
제가 고치겠습니다
Back in Qingqiu,
청구의 작은 오두막도
the little cabin often got battered by the wind.
예전에 바람만 세게 불면 금세 망가지곤 했는데
I was always the one fixing it.
모두 제가 손봤습니다
I can't believe Qingcheng
청성 사형도 참 그렇지
made you do all that work.
어찌 너에게 이런 일들을 시킨단 말이냐?
Sit down.
앉거라
That's nothing.
이건 아무것도 아닙니다
That old man had all sorts of quirks.
그 영감탱이는 괴상한 버릇이 한두 가지가 아니었습니다
He bragged without blinking an eye.
허풍은 입에 달고 살았고
He lost nearly every time he gambled.
도박은 열 번 하면 아홉 번은 잃기 일쑤였죠
Stingy and greedy.
게다가 구두쇠에 탐욕스럽기까지 해서
All day he just lay in his chair,
늘 의자에 비스듬히 기대어
smoking and dozing off.
곰방대만 문 채 꾸벅꾸벅 졸기 일쑤였지요
He was lazy
먹고 노는 것만 좋아하셨고
and picky about everything.
하루 종일 이것저것 트집만 잡았습니다
It was always something, like the radish being too bland
무 반찬이 싱겁다느니
or the tea being too hot.
찻물이 너무 뜨겁다느니 하면서요
He...
그분은...
But
그래도
our days were always so joyful
우리는 날마다 즐겁고 자유롭게 지냈습니다
and lively.
늘 시끌벅적했고
We lived better than immortals.
신선이 부럽지 않을 만큼 행복했지요
All these years, Qingcheng had you by his side.
그동안 네가 사형 곁을 지켜 준 덕분에
That's why he got to live such a happy life.
사형도 그렇게 즐거운 나날을 보낼 수 있었던 게다
I should thank you for him.
내가 사형을 대신해 너에게 감사하다는 말을 전하마
I'm the one who owes him.
제가 사부님께 진 빚이 얼마나 큰지 아십니까
He did so much for me.
사부님께서는 저를 위해 그토록 많은 것을 베풀어 주셨는데
But I never gave anything back.
저는 제대로 보답 한 번 못 했습니다
What are you saying?
보답을 못 했다니 무슨 소리냐?
You gave plenty.
그만하면 충분하다
He ate so much of your delicious cooking
그 양반이 지난 몇 년 동안 네가 해 준
over the years.
음식을 얼마나 많이 얻어먹었는데
Simo is always talking
사묵도 늘 입이 닳도록 칭찬했단다
about your chicken and mushroom stew.
네가 끓인 버섯 닭백숙이 먹고 싶다고 입버릇처럼 말하곤 했지
Have you seen
요 이틀간 사묵은 어디에 갔느냐?
Simo lately?
보았느냐?
No.
아니요
Simo's missing?
소사형이 보이지 않는다고요?
Haven't seen him lately.
요 이틀 동안 보이지 않는구나
Well, Master,
저, 사부님
I'll fix the cabin.
오두막은 제가 다녀와 고치겠습니다
You're still hurt.
아직 부상도 다 안 나으셨으니
Get some rest.
먼저 편히 쉬고 계세요
I'll be back soon.
얼른 다녀올게요
Leaving already?
이렇게 가느냐?
Qingcheng,
사형...
Lifei really takes after you.
려비의 성격이 참으로 사형을 쏙 빼닮았구려
Qingcheng.
사형
That kid's still as mischievous as ever.
이 녀석은 여전히 예전처럼 장난기가 넘칩니다
Qingcheng, Guangwei.
사형...
The child you two fought so hard to protect...
두 분이 목숨 바쳐 지켜 낸 저 아이가
I hope...
바라건대...
I hope she has fewer hardships ahead.
앞으로는 운명의 재난이 조금이나마 덜하기를 바랍니다
I asked the guards.
수위병들에게 물어봤다
When the demons retreated,
마족이 철수할 때
Ye Ye and Simo
엽엽과 사묵이
went after them.
마족의 흔적을 쫓아갔다더구나
They haven't come back.
아직 돌아오지 않았다
That was days ago.
벌써 며칠이나 지났는데
Could the demons have found them?
혹 마족에게 들킨 건 아닐까요?
Ye Ye carried a message talisman.
엽엽에게 전신부가 있으니
If anything had happened,
정말 무슨 일이라도 생겼다면
he would've let us know.
바로 우리에게 알렸을 거다
Since we haven't heard anything,
아직 소식이 없는 걸 보면
they probably haven't found the demons yet.
아직 마족의 행방을 찾지 못한 모양이야
Demons are vicious.
마족은 흉악하니
Better if they don't find them.
차라리 찾지 못하는 게 낫습니다
Zhaomin is already gone.
사저도 이미 세상을 떠났는데
If Simo and the others...
사묵마저도...
I've already sent people to search.
이미 사람들을 보내 찾게 했으니
We'll hear something soon.
조만간 소식이 올 거다
I'll go look again.
저도 더 찾아보겠습니다
My Lord.
존상
Your old friends followed us here.
오랜 벗이 찾아왔습니다
Qiongqi is entertaining them.
궁기가 인사를 드리겠다며 붙잡아 두었습니다
It's been seven full days.
벌써 꼬박 이레가 지났습니다
My Lord, when will you wake up?
존상께선 도대체 언제쯤 깨어나실 생각입니까?
I know
잘 압니다
the last person you want to hurt is Jiang Lifei.
존상께서 가장 해치고 싶지 않은 이가 강려비 아닙니까
I'll bring her to you.
제가 그 아이를 데려와 보게 하겠습니다
Any news from your side?
그쪽에는 무슨 소식이라도 있나?
The disciples I sent haven't reported back.
내가 보낸 제자들도
We can't find Ye Ye
아무런 소식이 없네
or the others either.
엽엽 일행도 찾을 길이 없고
Where could they have gone?
도대체 어디로 간 건지
Wait.
잠깐
There's demonic energy.
마기가 느껴지네
It's Ye Ye and the others' swords.
엽엽 일행의 검이네
If you don't want Ye Ye and his two companions to die,
엽엽을 비롯한 세 사람의 목숨을 살리고 싶다면
trade Jiang Lifei for them
내일 진시에
tomorrow at Chen hour
열렬곡 밖에서
outside Lilie Valley.
강려비를 데리고 나오거라
So they're there.
그곳에 붙잡혀 있었을 줄은...
I'm going now.
내 당장 가 보겠네
Don't rush.
충동적으로 굴지 마네
Demons are cunning and treacherous.
마족 놈들은 음험하고 간사하니
This could be a trap.
그들의 함정일지도 모르네
You're right.
듣고 보니 그렇군
Alright then.
그렇다면 이렇게 하지
I'll go scout things out.
내가 먼저 동태를 살피고 올 테니
Everyone else
다른 사람들은
stays put.
우선 움직이지 말고 대기하게나
And
참
don't tell Jiang Lifei.
강려비에게는 절대 비밀로 해야 하네
Excuse me.
사형
Where can I find Deng?
등 사형은 어디 계십니까?
She got so many disciples killed.
그 많은 사형제를 죽음으로 몰아넣고도
How dare she show up?
염치도 없이 이곳에 오다니
She's not even human.
인간이 아니라
What a plague.
화근이야
Let's go.
어서 가시게
Your Highness, your internal injuries haven't healed.
왕야, 내상도 다 낫지 않으셨으니
Don't go to Lilie Valley.
열렬곡에는 가지 마십시오
Tongzhou.
동주
Did you find Ye Ye and the others?
혹시 엽엽 일행을 찾으신 건가요?
Are they in Lilie Valley?
그들이 열렬곡에 있나요?
Someone spotted them nearby.
근처에서 그들을 보았다는 자가 있다
Deng Xiguang has already gone to check.
등계광이 이미 직접 확인하러 갔다
Then I need to go too.
그럼 저도 확인하러 가야겠어요
What's wrong?
왜 그러십니까?
Old injury flaring up?
옛 부상이 도진 것입니까?
You need to be careful.
어찌 이리 조심성이 없습니까
Let me see.
제가 한번 볼게요
I'm fine.
괜찮다
Sorry.
미안하다
I have to get stronger
내가 더 강해져야만
to protect you.
너를 온전히 지킬 수 있구나
Come here.
이리 오너라
Your Highness!
왕야
Your spirit energy came from Lifei.
네 영기는 본래 려비에게서 온 것이니
Only by drawing on her spirit energy
그 아이의 영기를 빌려야만
can you help me.
나를 도울 수 있다
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스하게 품어줄까♪
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪마음을 전할 길조차 없는데♪
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪Last night's stars cast faint glimmers♪
♪어젯밤 하늘을 수놓던 아스라한 별빛♪
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그때는 어찌 당연하게 여겼을까♪
♪With a heartbroken cry♪
♪가슴이 찢어지는 듯한 애달픈 외침으로♪
♪I wish you well♪
♪오직 그대의 안녕만을 바라네♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목 놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪Leaping straight into♪
♪내 기꺼이 이 몸을 던지리라♪
♪That heartbreaking past♪
♪살을 도려내는 듯한 아픈 기억 속으로♪
♪Just to keep you safe♪
♪그대만 무사할 수 있다면♪
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨결이 점차 희미해지고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪맞잡은 그 손을 더는 쥘 수 없으니♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 다가올 시린 바람과 안개를♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪이제 누구와 함께 견뎌내야 할까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪미소를 지으며 눈을 감는 것은♪
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪나로 인해 그대 슬피 울까 염려되어♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪말없이 공명등 한 줄기 빛이 되어♪
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪그대가 걷는 어두운 밤길을 비추어 주리♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
♪Torn inside, still I burn bright♪
♪가슴이 무너져 내릴지라도 참으로 감미롭구나♪
♪With the light from my fingertips♪
♪내 손끝에 맺힌 마지막 빛으로♪
♪I build a paradise♪
♪그대와 함께할 낙원을 세워♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪영원히 그대 곁을 거닐고 싶어라♪